We've all seen hundreds of bug bounty reports and we know that bug bounty can look very
easy.
But how does a life of an actual full-time bug bounty hunter look like?
To find this out, I interviewed Justin Gardner, who's one of the best hackers out there participating
in multiple live hacking events, who became full-time hunter about 4 years ago.
Trust me, you do not want to miss this episode.
Enjoy the interview.
Hello Justin, thank you so much for joining me in today's podcast.
For those of you who don't know Justin, he's a host among being a great bug bounty hunter.
He's the host of the Critical Thinking Bug Bounty podcast and I want to thank you and
Joel as well for creating such a fantastic resource.
I think it's literally the best resource about bug bounty at the moment.
So huge thanks for this.
That's awesome man.
Thank you.
Yeah of course, it's great to be on the pod man and it's fun actually being on the flip
side of this scenario, right?
Normally I'm the one being like, hey thanks for joining me on the pod and carrying the
conversation.
So I'm just going to sit back today and answer some questions and relax.
Should be fun.
Yeah, easy.
Almost easy job.
Actually it will be me just asking questions and listening to you and you'll do all the
hard work this time.
Well, that's true.
Okay, for those viewers who don't know you, they know they have to check Critical Thinking
but after this podcast and for now, can you please talk us through your background?
How did you start with hacking?
Sure man.
Yeah, so the background for me was, well I'm particularly blessed in that I knew what I
wanted to do for my job ever since I was like 12 years old.
And that all goes back to one day when I was working or I was playing my games when
I was 12 and a guy from my church actually came over when my internet stopped working
because I was like super, I was in the middle of a game and the internet just dropped and
I was like, oh this is terrible.
And a guy came over and he fixed my internet.
And he did that by typing into a little command line, you know the little black box command
line terminal and then all of a sudden, you know, it worked again.
And he typed like ipconfig slash release ipconfig renew and you know, just reset the lease there
and it worked.
And I was like, whoa, okay, hold on, I got to learn how to do that.
So I started Googling around and I started bothering him every week at church.
I'd be like, hey, teach me how to do this, teach me how to do this.
And so that was where the interest really started, but that was just IT.
So as I started, you know, learning more about computers, I started getting into programming
and as I started getting into programming, I started to get into hacking.
And at that time, it was largely me writing hacking tools in Python because I really liked
Python and I was the moderator of a forum called Hack Forums.
I was of the Python section of that.
And that was really fun.
And so I guess from there, it kind of, my interest sort of grew.
I did have my little stint on the dark side of hacking and, you know, went a little bit
down that path.
But after I decided that wasn't where I wanted to be ethically, I switched over to more focusing
on programming for the next couple of years.
And then after that, I went to college and restarted my hacking journey, which is where
I got acquainted with Bug Bounty.
And the story behind that is really interesting.
And I've actually, I think I've talked about this once or twice before, but that journey
actually started for me with a guy named Tommy DeVos, the dog EG, many, many people know
him in the community.
And he just kind of rolled into my cybersecurity club that I was teaching one day and started
telling me about Bug Bounty.
I didn't even know he was going to come.
And like, I was in the middle of teaching a lecture on how to, like, hack something
on Metasploitable.
And he just rolls in.
He's like, yo, what's up?
And in the middle of the lecture, and I'm like, hey, how's it going?
He's like, you guys want to pop some of these systems?
And he's pointing at these live computers.
I'm like, okay, who are you?
You know?
And he proceeded to tell me about Bug Bounty.
And that's kind of when my life changed.
And I did a little stint in, like, pen testing consulting, you know, before I jumped straight
into full-time Bug Bounty.
But really, from that moment on, from that moment that Tommy DeVos introduced me to it,
I've been really captivated by Bug Bounty.
And one question before we continue.
Where does your nickname come from?
Sure.
Yeah, man.
I get that question a lot.
And actually, Franz was kind of making fun of me.
At the last event, he put an emoji of, like, a person thinking, and then a rhinoceros,
and then, like, B+, or something like that.
Like, I'm rating rhinos, like, on a scale of, you know, F to A+, or whatever.
But actually, the name comes from a video game that I used to play called Ratcheting
Plank.
And in that game, there's a gun called the Rhino Blitzerator.
And being the weird 12-year-old that I was when I came up with this, I decided to take
the only cool part of that name out of it, and remove Blitz from it, and then just stick
with Rhino Rater.
So that's where it came from.
No correlation at all to rhinoceroses.
Okay.
It was a nice, nice, catchy nickname.
Thanks, man.
And the cool story behind it as well.
So you worked for a few years as a pen tester.
What were the things that attracted you in bug bounty that you didn't like in pen testing,
maybe?
Yeah, man.
Well, I really enjoyed my stint as a penetration tester.
I worked for a great company in Wisconsin called Synercom, S-Y-N-E-R-C-O-M-M.
And they're a great company.
I really enjoyed working with them.
I enjoyed the management and the whole flow.
But the thing that really pulled me away was the flexibility.
Like at the end of the day, if you're not working for yourself, you'll never have complete
flexibility.
And that's what I wanted.
So when Mariah and I were getting ready to move to Japan, which we did in 2020, I forced
myself to move out of my comfort zone a little bit and leave that job and go full-time bug
bounty because the financials were where they needed to be for that.
And I was definitely a little anxious about it at the time.
But with Mariah's support, we were able to do it.
How did you prepare to quit a nine-to-five job?
Well, you know, I'm pretty risk-averse as a person.
I'm kind of growing a little bit more away from that now.
But I was really not attracted to the idea of not having a consistent income.
And so for me, it looked like saving up a lot of money to make sure I had enough runway.
So essentially, Mariah and I said, OK, we're going to save up.
We're going to make sure that we have enough money to live in Japan for a year without
making any money at all off of bug bounty.
But at that point, I was already making more money off of bug bounty than I was making
at my full-time job.
And so, you know, it made sense that if I made the switch, I would be making at least
that much, if not more.
So that sort of confidence, you know, running those numbers, getting that runway in place,
that was a good thing for me.
And a lot of people mentioned the unpredictable income as one of the biggest cons of being
a full-time bug bounty hunter.
How do you manage this now?
Yeah, well, now it's a little bit more, I'm a little bit more comfortable with the whole
situation.
So I don't manage it as strictly as I did before.
But one of the best ways to manage this, and I talked about this on the last podcast that
we did at Critical Thinking with Renny Pak, is you can take some money, put it in a business
account, right?
Do bug bounty part-time until you build up, you know, however much you need in your business
account.
And then just decide, all right, I'm going to pay myself out, you know, 5K, 10K, 15K
a month, whatever it is, from this account to my bank account, just like I had a normal
job, you know?
And if you have enough runway in there in advance, if you've got, you know, let's say
if it's 5K, if you've got, you know, 30 grand, $30,000 in there, then you'll, you know, you've
got six months of runway of paying yourself without ever having to earn any money.
And that should be pretty stabilizing, I think.
Yeah, yeah, I did a similar thing.
When I was quitting my job, the way I thought about it is I have one year of worth of living
in my savings, and I treated every single, let's say, every single thousand was a few
days longer that I didn't have to come back to employment.
Exactly, exactly.
And then you pop bugs like that 20K S3 bucket thing, and then you extend that runway a lot.
Yeah, it extends a lot.
I don't even know how long it is now, but at least I do feel comfortable.
That's good.
And one more thing about the full-time bank bounty.
What are the things that make you reconsider your decision and make you want to be just
employed again and don't care about a lot of things?
Well, dude, you're asking me this question at a pretty, like, rough time, actually, for
me, because I've been sitting and thinking for the past couple days.
I'm coming off of a trip to Japan and off a trip to Portugal for some life hacking events,
and I'm just kind of now getting back into my swing.
And actually, when you asked me to prepare for this podcast, you asked me to grab some
stats on my bug bounty reports and that sort of thing.
And while my income is on track this year, I'm realizing that I'm not really a full-time
bug bounty hunter this year.
This year, I'm a full-time live hacking event participant is essentially what's happening.
Looking back over my reports, they are very much largely clustered around the live hacking
events.
And then after that, I take a break, or as I mentioned on the pod before, I do real estate
stuff on the side.
So this year in January, we bought a rental property, and I've been fixing that up, going
there, hammering stuff and drilling stuff and that sort of thing, and we just finally
finished that.
So I haven't been quite on top of it this year, and that affects the confidence a little.
I'm still doing all right in the live hacking events, but when you're not staying in the
requests every single day, and you're not getting as much time, and I think it's also
coupled with the fact that I've been doing critical thinking, which takes time.
I'm just not as in the request as I used to be.
And so that's something that I'm taking steps to fix, but in the meantime, it feels a little
bit like that feeling starts to creep back a little bit, that familiar feeling of, man,
is this really the right choice for me?
And I know I'm ranting here, but I actually do have one other thing.
Starting full-time book bounty, I think it's really tricky to be self-employed and to rest
properly, because I find it really hard for me to say, all right, six o'clock, and then
I'm done, if I've got stuff that I need to do.
And so yesterday, it was a beautiful fall day, and I got the hot tub in the backyard,
and I'm like, okay, I'm just gonna grab a drink, be done with work, grab a drink, Mariah's
coming with me, we go sit out in the hot tub, drink the drink, look at the beautiful
fall colors, and I'm sitting there, and I'm like, man, this is great, but why am I still
feeling a little anxiousness in my chest, you know?
I know it so well.
It's bad, man, and so it takes a lot of mental effort, and a lot of mental, and so I sat
there in that moment, and I said, hey, breathe, like, you have enough time to do the work
that you need to do, you have enough income to survive, why are you stressing out?
There's no reason, right?
And so sometimes you just gotta take a breath, breathe through it, and meditate on that fact
that everything is fine, and you don't need to worry about all these little details.
And I didn't have that problem before when I was employed, traditionally, when I had
a consulting job, because at the end of the day, I'd clock out, and I'd be like, well,
this is somebody else's problem now, you know?
So it's definitely different, and those things like that do make me question the decision
a little bit every once in a while.
Yeah, it's difficult to relax without, to like fully relax.
For me, I think sports is great, because then I'm literally so into whatever activity I
am doing that I can't even think this.
Yeah, yeah.
But it's definitely difficult.
I play volleyball every week.
I was playing volleyball until midnight last night, and it's great.
But for me, that's not rest.
It's mental rest, but sometimes not even mental rest, because it's like there's a lot of strategy
that goes into volleyball, and I'm a very competitive person, and so when I'm playing
volleyball, I'm in the zone.
I think trying to figure out how to have strict boundaries with yourself, and actually, here,
let me show you one other trick.
For those of you listening on, I'm sorry, but I'm going to show something on the screen
here for YouTube.
This is a sign that my wife got me, and this says in Japanese, open for business, and this
one says closed, or planned days off, essentially.
And when I'm working, I flip the sign to in business, and when I'm done working, I flip
the sign to it's rest time, and that does help me sort of mentally segregate, all right,
I need to be done with work now, and I need to stop letting it invade my thoughts and
invade my stress.
Yeah, it's so smart, because being self-employed just creates a lot of problems like this,
that you are not even thinking about when you're quitting.
When you're quitting, you're thinking about, will I make enough money, I will be able to
travel, and you just don't think that, oh yeah, this might be a problem that I don't
know where should I finish.
Yeah, yeah, it's rough, man, and also taking time off, I take a decent amount of time off,
I do, but I feel like I'm not taking very much time off, because even when I'm taking
time off, it's like, well, you know, things aren't going on without me, you know, and
so it's a little bit, until you get some employees in your business that are actually keeping
business running, it sort of stops when you're a solo entrepreneur, and that's a little bit
stressful too, so taking time off and finding time to rest after work hours, I think is
difficult as an entrepreneur.
Yeah, and we have to play volleyball when we meet at any live hacking events, I started
playing this year after not playing for years, because I was in Tenerife doing the Digital
Nomad thing, and there was a nice group of people playing volleyball, and I started loving
the game back after so many years of break, and now I try to play like once in a week,
I love the beach volleyball, but I play indoor as well.
Yeah, dude, I love volleyball, it's always been, you know, ever since I started playing
in a rec league when I was like 16, it's been my favorite sport by far, it's just this perfect
combination of like, it's very clutch, you know, there's lots of very, there's very like
dangerous situations where you can like kind of barely survive, you know, and dive and
get the ball back over the net, and it's also very collaborative, you know, you have to
work with a team, and there's nothing more gratifying than like, being a hitter, and
then seeing that set go up, and it's a beautiful set, and you're like, oh, I'm about to crush
that, you know, and then just, boom, you know, I love it, I love it.
Yeah, I feel when I jump, when I get the timing correct, and I jump when I shoot, I just feel
just before, before the attack, I just feel it will be a good one.
Oh, yeah, dude, I love that feeling so much.
And then I'm blocked.
Yeah, exactly, that happened last night, I got such a good swing in, and somebody just
boop, blocked it down, bummer.
Yeah, okay, let's get back to hacking.
Attacking both is nice, but how do you attack web applications, what's your hacking style?
Yeah, you know, I find this question really hard to answer, because it's a pretty abstract
question, and I kind of put some thought into it, and I think the biggest thing for me is
actually understanding the application, and understanding how users use the application.
So first thing I do when I get into an application is I get excited, and then I think I'm about
to start hacking stuff, and I start looking at the request, and sometimes I'll like read
the JavaScript files right off the bat, and then I almost always catch myself about five
minutes in, and I'm like, okay, let's actually not try to hack something that we don't
understand.
And I go back, and I minimize my Kydo tab, or my birth tab, or whatever, and send it
down to the bottom, and where I can't look at it, and then I just use the application
like a user, and I try to set through all the functionality in the application, I try
to configure everything, sometimes that means going and creating accounts on different services,
and linking those accounts to this service, and importing data, or filling out spreadsheets
to populate data in the application, whatever it is.
I take the time to do that for a little while, and then I go back, and I start looking through
the request in Burp, and I start working back through those same things, but with the window
open, and that's when the bugs start rolling, but I think it's important first to use the
application like a human, and not necessarily just like somebody who's focused on hacking
it.
How much time does this phase last, more or less?
You know, normally about, normally less than an hour, I'd say.
You know, it depends on the size of the application, but normally less than an hour, and then also,
I won't necessarily do this while I'm hacking, but I'll try to, but sometimes I will, but
I often try to read the documentation too, and that's a great thing to do, like, you
know, if you have to go somewhere, and you know, your wife is driving or something, and
you can just read the documentation on your phone, or like you're waiting at a doctor's
appointment or something like that, and you know, you can just read the documentation,
and so that's when I'm feeling a little bit, or maybe I'm like burnt out on hacking, my
eyes don't want to look at the screen anymore, so I, you know, throw the, you know, documentation
on my e-reader, my e-ink reader, and then go sit in the hot tub and read the documentation,
you know, and so it works great for getting to know the application a little bit better,
and as we say on the podcast, getting intimate with the application, you know, and I think
that's really important.
I'm not much of a wide hacker.
I don't do a lot of recon.
I mostly just go to the main app and then hack it, sort of person.
Do you take notes when you're in the hot tub, for example?
I don't, I don't.
What I will do sometimes is I will record a voice memo, and then, you know, just kind
of record, and then pause, and then go back to the documentation, record, pause, go back
to the documentation, that sort of thing, and then afterwards, I'll either have that
transcribed by AI, or I'll transcribe it myself, or sometimes I'll send it to Mariah, and she'll
transcribe it for me, and that does help, but normally, while I'm hacking, my notes
are nothing more than naming my Kaido tabs or something like that, so yeah.
And it's a very difficult question, because you probably rely on your experience a lot,
but what are you looking for in this first phase when you're assessing the application?
Yeah, man, that's a good question.
Yeah, you hit the nail on the head when you said relying on experience, and I think what's
really important for a lot of people is building that experience, right?
And the only way you build that experience is by failing, and so get out there, fail,
look at the applications, but for me, I'm looking for anything that has an ID in the
request, right?
So I can try IDORS, I'm looking for data that's being reflected in the response.
Specifically, in older applications, you can just kind of feel it when they reflect
data into a JavaScript block.
One of the things I see a lot is a query parameter or a post parameter gets put inside a variable,
so in JavaScript, in the response, right?
And that's just sketchy as heck.
And so whenever you have those sort of situations, definitely look for XSS.
I'm looking for places where URLs are being parsed.
That's not great stuff.
I'm looking for any tokens or signed things, right?
So I can see if I can manipulate any of that, trying to break out of that syntax.
What else am I looking for?
Looking for any XML parsing or really any structured language parsing or any interactions
with SDKs or other logical entities.
If they're using a different website to do XYZ, there's got to be sort of an auth transition
between those two things.
And that's kind of where I'm looking.
And Dan, what are your favorite bug types that you go for most often?
Favorite bug types.
Well, lately, I've been loving postMessage stuff.
The postMessage stuff is really cool.
And there's a lot of untapped attack surface there.
So I really like that.
To be honest, man, I think my favorite bugs are the ones that are irregular.
You know, the ones that are not your IDOR, your SSRF, your RCE, your straightforward,
you know, just like command injection or anything like that.
It's something that, like, all right, I, like, inject it into this token, and this token,
like, gives me half auth into this other app.
And then, like, with that half auth, I found, like, this one little weird endpoint in the
API that I can hit that just, like, leaks everything.
You know, that sort of stuff is a lot more engaging or a lot more exciting to me now
than, like, ah, look at this.
I found an IDOR, you know, sort of thing.
Yeah.
And I know that you are probably the most famous user of Kaido.
What sort of...
Do you spend all the time in Kaido, or do you use both Verb and Kaido?
What does it look like?
Yeah, I use both right now.
I would like to switch fully to Kaido, and I use Kaido normally until I need to use Verb.
But there are still a couple features missing with Kaido, and I think a lot of this will
be solved when Kaido implements upstream proxies, which is coming out very soon.
I think you released a podcast, like, two hours ago when we record this about Kaido.
Yeah, so there's lots of good data in there about Kaido.
But yeah, they're going to be implementing upstream proxies soon, which will allow you
to chain Kaido with Verb and that sort of thing, which you can already do with Verb
upstream proxies.
But, you know, I prefer to use Kaido as the main one.
And then I'm using Verb primarily now for things like quick collaborator callbacks if
I need it, but really rarely that.
And then for ParamMiner and some of the plugins.
That's the main thing that I think I'm missing in Kaido is the plugin functionality that
Verb has.
There are a couple other nice-to-haves, but at the end of the day, I'm working to transition
my flow from Verb into Kaido and trying to grow with that product because I'm 100% certain
that it will be taking over the market.
Yeah, I think there's a lot of room for a different proxy right now because Verb has
so many functionalities and it's so great in many aspects, but it's also bad in many
aspects.
And there's room for competition.
And I think one way or another, when we have competition, we as users, we are going to
win when they fight.
Fight for the audience.
100%, man.
Yeah, I totally agree.
And no disrespect to Portswiger.
I talk about Kaido all the time, but Portswiger is a great company.
They do so much cool stuff at the Portswiger Academy, and I love the Portswiger Research
Twitter channel and that sort of thing.
I feel like there are some things we've been asking for with Verb for a while for them
to solve the structural issues and how much computing power is required to run it.
And it's just not happening.
So there's definitely a space for someone else to move into the market, even if it's
just in the capacity of a lightweight HTTP proxy, right?
It doesn't necessarily have to be everything.
A lot of hackers, that's all they need.
A repeater is the main functionality, so something can work.
Absolutely.
What are some Verb extensions that you use most commonly?
Verb extensions, param minor.
Param minor is my go-to one.
Let me just hold on.
Let me just open it up here and see what I've got.
Yeah, so param minor.
I actually use copy as Python requests pretty often, just to pop it out into a Python file.
I use this great plugin called Request Minimizer, which is super helpful.
And essentially what it does is you just click one button, and it sends the request a bunch
of times, and then it tells you which cookies, which headers, whatever, are necessary for you
to get the same response.
And that's really helpful in allowing you to identify what is actually doing something
in the situation, right?
What cookies are being used for auth?
What headers are being used for auth?
You know, what the CSRF restrictions are actually being implemented, that sort of thing.
So I use that one.
I've got JS Weasel on here.
Autorepeater is really cool too, if you're working on an app that does a lot of auth
testing.
So that one's really cool as well.
What does autorepeater do?
Yeah, autorepeater is really cool.
It essentially allows you to automatically repeat requests.
And so essentially what it does is you define a set of replacements.
For example, if you want the cookies from another account subbed into the request, then
it can do that, and it'll automatically sub, like, CSRF headers and that sort of thing
if you set it up to do that.
And then it'll repeat the request.
And the reason why this is really cool is you can automate, I guess, authorization testing.
And so, you know, I just set up, all right, here are the cookies for my second account.
Here's a CSRF token that matches the cookies in the second account.
And every request that I do, it'll sub the cookies, sub the CSRF token in, and tell me
whether I get a 403 or a 200 and log the response.
And it has a nice, you know, red-green sort of indicator to determine whether the request
was successful or not.
So if you're dealing with an app that has a lot of problems with authorization, then
this can really speed up your testing methodology, because you won't have to send it to repeater,
sub the cookies, sub the CSRF token every time.
It'll just be done automatically.
It sounds, like, very similar to Authorize extension.
Did you test both of them, or...
Let me see.
Yep, that's the one I'm talking about.
I'm talking about Authorize.
I have both of them on next to it, next to each other here.
But yeah, that's the one that...
I'm actually talking about Authorize.
Yeah.
Okay, yeah, yeah.
Authorize is great.
I also use it.
You also said something about not reading JS files in the initial phase of testing the
app, but when the time comes, eventually, to read the JS files, what are your tips to
get the most out of them?
Yeah, so, JS files are really, really important.
They are one of the top ways, I think, to get intimate with an application.
And so, in order to do that effectively, there's a couple really good tips, and JS
Weasel is implementing a lot of them.
It's a really expensive software, and there are, once again, features missing from it
that have prevented me from integrating it into my workflow, like, full-fledged.
But once it does complete those features, for example, a global search and a little
bit more clean UI, I think it'll be huge.
And the reason for that is because so many applications nowadays are using a webpack
to sort of encapsulate their JS files, right?
And you need to write a script to take the map for that, which you can find in one of
the files, and build out all the sub-JS files that are lazy-loaded, and get all those as
well.
And then once you do, you can find a bunch of really cool endpoints in those.
And that's really the goal of it all, right?
Is to look at the JavaScript files, look at the functionality that's there, or maybe used
to be there, if it's commented out, and try to see if those endpoints exist on the server
side, and whether you can recreate that functionality.
And there's lots of different tricks to that, but the primary ones that I can think of now
are look for, take a request that you see going through Kaido or through Burp, and send
it to, you know, send it to repeater, look at the URL, and try to find the JS file or
the JS code that initialized that request.
And then essentially look at the format, look at how that HTTP request is being issued,
maybe it's fetch, maybe it's, you know, AJAX, maybe it's whatever, and then search for that
same functionality, for that same code, in all the JS files, to see if you can enumerate
all of the ways that requests are being sent in the application.
And do you usually do this inside the browser?
Like, let's say, without the JS Weasel?
Yeah, I do.
Yeah, I almost always do.
And there's some really big benefits of that, namely that you can set breakpoints and do
dynamic analysis as well.
But yeah, I would like to do it in JS Weasel, because it's nice to have some of the VS code
functionality.
But like I said, for me, it's just not quite there yet.
I could see it getting there within the next six months, for sure.
Do you pay for this?
Or did you use the free trial?
Yeah, I've used the free trial.
And I told Charlie, I said, hey, man, you know, trial's up.
For right now, I don't think I'm going to be able to integrate it into my workflow, but
implement these features.
And then if you can give me another trial, I would strongly consider buying this.
And you get a lot of other big names in the industry, Shubbz, CDL.
These guys are already using it, I believe, on a regular basis.
So it's definitely a product to keep your eye on and something that very well might be
worth $1,000 a year.
Yeah, OK.
So let's say you did all these things and three, four, five, six, seven, the whole day
passes, you didn't find the bug.
What's the moment when you say enough and you move on to another one?
Dude, I'm not the guy to ask this question, too, because I will not move on until I find
a bug.
And then I will start grasping at straws until I find something.
In one of the latest live hacking events that I've been to, there's this particularly
featureless application that we were supposed to hack.
And everyone was like, yeah, this is really not much here.
And I just could not let it go until I found something.
And then I found some crazy...
I won't give the details, but it was very much grasping at straws in the beginning,
but turned into a pretty decent bug.
But yeah, for me, I think really it would have to be two weeks if I wasn't finding...
I really do not like to let applications defeat me.
So I would keep on digging as long as the bounties were there.
I'm not going to dive two weeks on a 5k crit program, but as long as the bounties are there,
1k for medium, something for a high, and then above 5k, ideally 10k or above for a crit,
then I'll definitely spend some time on that.
You also said in one podcast that when you started to spend more time on one application,
you started finding fewer bugs, but more critical bugs.
Yeah, yeah.
That's definitely true.
I think that if you look at my reports from 2021 or 2020,
or 2020, a lot of my reports were volume.
Find every single IDOR, find every single XSS, that sort of thing, right?
But then as I started to look at it less as a grind of checking every single endpoint,
every single parameter, and looking at it more holistically from an application perspective,
and saying, okay, where is the valuable data in this application?
What are the core pieces of functionality?
What are the fringe pieces of functionality that affect core pieces of functionality,
like the developer API or something like that, right?
That's when I started finding more complex, more intriguing, and higher impact bugs,
but less of them, for sure.
Yeah, but overall, you're probably happy with finding fewer critical bugs.
Yeah, yeah, I am.
And sometimes it doesn't work out that way, and sometimes you spend your time,
and you just find mediums, and lows, and maybe a high or two,
and that's sometimes how it goes.
But yeah, I'm always shooting for the higher impact,
and trying not to shy away from the complex topics as well.
That's another tip, is like, if you read something in the documentation,
or you see something in an app, and it looks complex, and it looks difficult to hack,
guess what?
Every other hacker also thought that.
And I bet you that the people that did the pen testing for that application also thought that,
and said, ah, you know, my 40 hours on this app are better spent elsewhere.
And there are often bugs there.
The reason why I placed fourth in the last Integrity event was,
I focused on a more complex part of the scope,
and was able to land two bugs there that paid out really well.
So definitely a good tip there.
Okay, so for example, how many programs did you hack for at least a few days in the last,
let's say, a month, excluding the period now where you prepared for the live hacking event?
Yeah, so let's take a look at that.
I've got some data up here.
So I did some hacking on BARD, and that was really fun.
And I did some live hacking event prep, and then I did one other program.
And that's, yeah, that's in the last month.
About three programs.
And I guess...
That's not a lot.
Sometimes I go through three in one day.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, I would never do that.
Like, I have to spend at least a couple days on a program.
And for me, it's a little bit frustrating, too, because a program recently launched,
and this is one I was hacking a couple days ago.
And, you know, it's new scope.
And so it was just a bloodbath, right?
There were worms everywhere.
And I got, besides one crit and one high, I got all dupes.
And the reason for that was I'm slow to find the bugs.
I mean, it's just kind of who I am as a hacker.
Like, I'm not, I don't have that sixth sense that some people tend to have,
in that they go into the application and they just know right away where the bugs are, you know?
And sometimes it's luck.
But there are some hackers that I know that really are just like,
no, I wouldn't even test that because there's not going to be bugs.
I would test this place for bugs, and there's bugs there.
And I'm like, what?
And so I definitely am a little bit more methodical with my going in there,
reading the docs, using the application like a user.
But a lot of times that ends up, especially when there's no dupe window,
with me getting some dupes on the more lower hanging fruits.
But I still got the crit and the high,
which came from a little bit more in-depth application analysis.
Yeah, and so when you want to spend so much time on a program that you choose,
it must be a really thought out decision to hack on the program.
So what are the factors that you consider when choosing your program?
Yeah, normally it's a live hacking event invite.
Yeah, to be frank, the past year it's been that.
But besides that, I really enjoy the Instacart program.
We might have to bleep that.
I don't remember if they're public or not.
OK.
And that program is great.
I've enjoyed working with them.
And the bounties are where they should be.
And I'm a little bit more acquainted with the application, which is nice.
And then also, I do look at the challenges.
And I do look at programs that are just launching.
And if the bounties are enticing, then I'll go for those.
And what that looks like for me is if the mediums are above $750.
So ideally, I would like them at like $1,000.
Some programs have mediums up to $3,000, which is really, really nice.
And then if the crits are in the, I say above $5,000,
I really would like to see them above $7,500 now.
If the crit is below $7,500, it feels a little bit not as rewarding.
Because you can go to companies like PayPal and get a medium,
and it's like $8,000.
And so that's kind of what I look for.
And do you spend more time on private or public bug bounty programs?
Definitely private.
Private.
And do you sort of...
So when an invite comes to your inbox, and you evaluate the program,
what are the metrics on, let's say, HackerOne that you look at?
Do you look at the response time?
Do you look at the leaderboard?
Yeah.
So first of all, when I get a program invite,
there's a lot of program invites that are coming.
So I'm not really even assessing all of them nowadays.
I just kind of click, accept, click, accept, click, accept.
And then when I'm looking for a new program,
I'm going to my opportunities tab.
And sometimes I'm sorting by most recent programs,
and then I'll sort of read through those a little bit.
And I'll look at the bounty table, like I mentioned, that sort of thing.
And I'll look at the response statistics.
Now, my response statistics criterion has changed a little bit over the years.
I used to like to see sub two-week response time.
And I still do, of course.
But my standard has moved a little bit more lax, too.
If they can get me the bounty within a month, I'm pretty happy with that.
If there was a program that would pay, you know, in two weeks,
then I think they would get a lot more engagement.
But times are changing,
and people seem to be a little bit understaffed in their security departments.
So some of my favorite programs that had a more traditionally fast response time
aren't keeping it up nowadays.
Okay, and do you have some programs that you come back over and over again?
Yeah, Instacart's the one, man.
That's the one that I kind of go and work on.
Besides that, there are a couple companies that have been running challenges iteratively.
You know, they run challenges on a pretty regular basis.
Challenges being, they'll launch new scope.
They'll launch a new product into scope and run a specific program for that
that is capped at a specific amount of money.
So, you know, they'll say, okay, we've got this challenge.
It's new scope.
It's capped at 25 grand or whatever.
So I'll normally try to participate in those
if they're one of the couple ones that I really like.
But most of the time for me, it's live hacking event targets or Instacart.
Okay, and let's say you come back to a program after a year.
Do you sort of start from the beginning, like you never hacked here before?
Or do you have something that you track changes?
Do you check release notes?
Yeah, I definitely check release notes on my targets that I am aware of.
And that's always really helpful.
I'm also doing this thing, and I don't think the script's running nowadays,
but for like one or two targets.
But I will be picking up this thing again, where I, when I'm hacking on a target,
and I did that sort of JS parsing, like I mentioned before of like,
all right, this is how endpoints are defined in the JavaScript files on this target, right?
I will set up an automation script to go to the HTML page
that contains the dynamically generated JS file, extract the JS file name,
open up the JS file, and then run a set of regexes on it.
And extract all the endpoints out.
And then yeah, that's so smart.
Diff that with an old version of that same data.
And then alert if anything new pops up.
So I'm getting alerted to new endpoints, new, you know, GraphQL queries and mutations.
I'm getting alerts for sometimes even feature flags on the application,
you know, that sort of thing.
So those will allow me to be a little bit more reactive in my hacking
and go after some of those new features right as they come out.
Yeah, that's so good.
Like now I think about it is the best approach to dishing JS files that I've heard about.
Recently, there was a guy that found a 2Hacker one,
a report 2Hacker one about an IDOR in an unreleased feature.
And he did maybe not similar thing,
but he just extracted words from JS files and diffed them.
But I think with your approach,
with actually having it sort of tailored regex to a specific application,
I think that's the most accurate approach to it that I've seen.
Yeah, and I'll give some tips to people that are thinking about implementing the same thing.
I don't know that I'll ever make my version of this open sourced.
But if anybody is thinking about making the same thing,
I would advise you to not try to make a one size fits all system
where you just like input a bunch of variables and then it does it.
I would advise you to build a library
that allows you to have an easier time building these scripts,
but to build an individual script for every target.
Because every target is going to have a different structure, a different flow.
Are you logging in, automating a login,
and then going and grabbing a HTML file that has a JS file in it?
Or are you doing that same thing, but when you grab the JS file,
then you're extracting parts of the JS file and then you're loading it in?
Extracting parts of the JS file and then building more JS files and going getting in those?
You know, there's lots of different iterations for you to do a very thorough analysis of
the JS files that the company is producing.
And I think your best bet is actually just to write custom code for each and every one
and have some tools in your toolkit that will allow you to do that effectively.
Yeah, and from the technical side, do you just run this script on your VPS or something?
Yeah, I...
And you use maybe Slack notifications?
Yeah, exactly. I use a webhook and I just have it in CronTab on my VPS
and it just runs every, you know, five minutes or ten minutes or an hour, whatever I decide.
And yeah, and the other cool thing about that is you get to know the company's release cycle too.
So you'll see like, hey, I'm getting notifications about this every Thursday at,
you know, 6 p.m. or something like that.
So I bet they're pushing every Thursday at 6 p.m., you know, and so that's pretty cool as well.
Yeah, interesting. How often do you run it? Do you run it every hour?
Yeah, every hour, sometimes every five to ten minutes.
But that's kind of overkill. I would recommend doing it every hour.
Okay, but do you think if someone does it every day, it's too... it's not enough?
No, not necessarily. You know, I just like to catch it as soon as I can catch it, right?
Because it's a competitive game, you know, we're looking to, you know,
we're looking to beat other hackers to this scope.
And who knows, the other hacker could just be, you know, wandering onto that program that day.
And but you got to react quickly if you want to be first to some of these things, so.
Okay. Is it the only automation that you run these days?
Yeah, that's pretty much it, man. Everything else is manual.
I, just for, yeah, just for a little bit of history,
I was a competitor in the Recon game for many years.
You know, I had my full setup with my, you know, pulling from passive DNS sources,
doing certs, you know, TLS certs, and, you know, brute forcing stuff.
And then, you know, doing subdomain takeovers and scanning mass for vulnerabilities.
But for me, it got too much of a grind.
And I discovered that I was spending more time writing code than I was actually hacking stuff.
And I didn't like that very much.
So when my bread and butter vulnerability type, the Route 53 takeovers,
had a big sort of structural change that made them more tricky to implement.
They're still possible, I believe, but definitely trickier to implement.
Then I said, all right, let me try to pivot a little bit.
And that's when I started doing a little bit more intentional manual hacking
and looking for more impactful vulnerabilities.
But I will say lately, I've been kind of thinking about flipping back to the other side,
for that same reason that we talked about, Greg, which is that
if you stop working, nothing's happening, right?
And I was always comforted by the fact that when I wasn't working,
when I had my, you know, automation setup running,
that something was always searching for vulnerabilities.
And sometimes I'd get that ping on my phone, like,
oh, subdomain takeover, you know, great, you know.
And that was a little bit comforting.
So I think, you know, maybe expanding this JS file monitoring that I'm doing
to more programs or getting back into the automation game just a little bit,
scanning for a couple of different types of vulns
might help me sort of relieve that stress a little bit.
Yeah, I sometimes think about it when I'm talking with somebody about the career
and bug bounty hunting and doing the YouTube stuff and blah, blah, blah.
And sometimes we delve into the passive income discussion.
And when I say, you know, when you're hacking,
you have to be in front of the computer and then,
yeah, I should probably exclude the automation guys from this
because they can actually make money passively.
Yeah, man, it's pretty awesome.
And that was the fun part of all that.
So it's great for those hackers that really enjoy writing code, for sure.
Yeah, let's come back to live hacking events.
You said that this year was mostly oriented around those hacking events.
So for those of us who haven't attended live hacking events,
how does this cycle look like?
Yeah, well, to be honest, the flow of the live hacking events,
like when they occur and where they're going to be and stuff like that,
we, you know, sometimes we know in advance,
but most of the time we just know when HackerOne announces it,
like, you know, on their Twitter or by sending us invites to our emails, right?
And so not a lot of planning in advance on that.
And that's feedback I've given to HackerOne being like,
hey, especially if you want me to come to every event in a year,
you know, five or six events in a year,
I need to know more in advance so I can plan my life a little bit.
But yeah, so the typical flow is you get an email saying,
hey, you're invited to the event, here's the details.
Sometimes they'll tell you the target then
or they'll release the target at a later date.
It's going to be in this place.
You're covered for your flight and hotel
or you're not covered for your flight and hotel,
depending on whether you're a plus one
or whether you're sort of a sponsored hacker.
And then probably about two weeks before the live hacking event swings around,
you get on a scope call.
They announce the scope, they tell you about the bonuses
and the cool, you know, bounty tables and challenges
and that sort of thing to have planned for the event.
Is this called the first time when you see what other hackers are invited?
Yeah, sort of.
But, you know, it gets around in the community, you know.
Yeah, I guess.
You kind of know.
And there are, you know, people like me and Joel
that have gone to like every event since like, you know, 2018 or something like that.
So, you know, there's definitely some regulars.
But yeah, then you have the scope call,
you kind of say hey to all your friends
and you kind of decide, hey, am I going to collab
or am I not going to collab?
And then right after the scope call, the scope opens normally.
So, you know, you get the invite and you start hacking.
Then it's two weeks of hardcore hacking.
And this is what's called, this phase is what's called the dupe window.
So, if anybody finds a bug that is the same as another bug during this period,
the bounty is split in half.
And so, you know, if I find a bug and you find the same bug during that period
and that bug is awarded a 2k bounty, then we'll each get $1,000.
But here's a little bit of catch to that, right?
Say me and Joel are collaborating and you do it solo, right?
That bug gets split in two.
So, you get $1,000 and then we get $1,000,
which then gets split to $500, right?
So, there's lots of dynamics surrounding collaboration.
And we all know the power of collaboration.
It definitely allows you to...
Sorry, just to clarify this,
if three independent hackers or four independent hackers find a bug,
it's split into three or four?
Yes, that's correct.
Yeah.
Is there an upper limit for...
There is not.
And so, I have some emails in my inbox of saying,
hey, you were awarded an $8 bounty or like a $4 bounty.
And I'm like, thanks, appreciate that.
But yeah, so, you know, there's definitely some collaboration stuff
that needs to be taken into account there.
And then after the dupe window is over,
most of the time people, you know, you'll kind of hit up your friends.
You'll be like, hey, what did you find?
And they'll be like, hey, what did you find?
And you kind of share cool bugs.
And then collaboration opens up a lot more at that point, I think,
because people have done their initial pass
and they're looking to escalate things
and they're looking to see the things they missed.
And then, you know, you go to the event,
you collab, the bounties start rolling.
And then the award ceremony happens where, you know, an MVH is decided.
The MVH is decided.
And it's a very exciting time for sure.
Do you usually work alone at live hacking events?
Do you collaborate?
Are you part of a bigger team?
Yeah, man.
So I catch a lot of flack for this, actually, but I don't normally collab.
The only exception to that is when I have,
when Joel decides to take time off of work and do it full time with me,
then I'll do a 50-50 split with Joel,
because I know him and I know what kind of hacker he is.
And I think we complement each other well.
But typically for me, I'm going solo until the end of the dupe period.
And the reason for that is I think I have the ability
to find a good amount of bugs solo.
And like I mentioned before, if you find a bug on a team,
not only are, and that bug is duped,
not only are you getting the dupe split,
but you're also getting the collab split, right?
So the bounties get a lot lower.
So what I prefer to do is I prefer to work solo until the end of the dupe period.
And then at the end of the dupe period, I'll collab with other hackers.
And then at that point, if we're finding bugs that are unique,
then we can submit those together
and then just get the full bounty split
between however many of us participated in it.
And that's been a good system for me over the past couple of years.
And I think it maximizes bounty returns
and still allows me to see a lot of cool bugs
and collaborate with a lot of great hackers.
Do you think those dupe windows could work outside live hacking events?
Frick yes, I do.
I'm so salty right now because of all those dupes I got
in that program that I was telling you about when a program launches.
I would love to see HackerOne implement dupe windows in challenges
and in, you know, just when programs launch,
because it motivates hackers a lot more.
For example, the target that I'm talking about,
it launched in the middle of the night for me.
And so I missed a lot of the, you know,
initial hacking hours on that program.
And I like to think that's why I got, you know,
more dupes than my fair share there.
But yeah, I would definitely like to see that be used in other contexts as well.
What are some other things or features in bug bounty platforms
that you'd like to see?
That's a good question.
Well, I'm lucky enough to have had the opportunity to collab directly with
designers for HackerOne and for other platforms as well.
And give direct feedback on the stuff that I want implemented.
And so most of the features that I've really been kind of yearning for
have been implemented already.
You know, off the top of my head,
the only thing that comes to mind is a little bit more in-depth reporting
and a better mobile UI,
which is a complaint that I've had for a while,
is that the HackerOne mobile UI is like not great.
But I would definitely also...
How often do you use it on mobile?
I use it on mobile all the time.
So like responding to reports?
Yeah, responding to reports.
And also just, you know, I'm out and about
and I get an email saying, you know,
there's some movement on this report.
You know, it's like crack, man.
You start shaking if you don't open the email right away, you know.
So I use it on mobile a lot.
Okay.
Coming back to the live hacking event,
imagine the situation that you lose all your bug bounty platform profiles
and you lose all the relationships you have,
but you keep your skills.
What's the fastest way to get to a live hacking event?
That's a good question.
If I'm being honest,
the fastest way to get to a live hacking event
is probably to connect with other hackers
that are at the live hacking events.
So whether that's, you know, you try to...
Well, also hackers get in...
Notable hackers that are in the locality of the event
also get invited.
So for example, if they're having an event in Washington, D.C.,
I'm an hour from Washington, D.C.
So I might get an invite there,
even though I'm not like, you know,
the top hacker in general at that point, right?
And so, you know, your locality definitely plays a role,
but your best chance at getting in,
I believe, is probably to be a plus one in the beginning, right?
And so making friends with somebody that has a plus one
and asking for a plus one or that sort of thing
can get you in the door.
But then here's the thing,
you've got to perform at that event, you know?
If you don't rank top 10 at that event,
unlikely you're getting back in.
And so that's kind of how I got into the events
in the first place was I was a plus one.
And then I ranked eighth in my first live hacking event.
And then I got invited to the next one.
And the next one, I had enough time to like fully prepare
and hack.
And then I've kind of continued ranking in the top 10
for the next live hacking events
until I won an MVH and a couple of first place trophies.
And that kind of secures your place a little bit more.
Yeah.
Also, now I think back to sort of your hacking style
that you don't report as much volume,
but you go for the impact more.
It's probably not the best ways
to optimize for reputation points on those platforms.
So yeah, now it makes sense for you.
Well, let me clarify that really quickly.
Like I report every bug I find.
Don't get me wrong.
Like every, you know, if there's a low,
I'm going to report that shit all day, you know?
And so it's not that I'm not looking for...
I'm definitely focusing on impact.
I'm trying to achieve impact.
But I definitely don't shy away from reporting,
you know, lows or mediums or anything like that
at the expense of spending more time
finding highs or criticals.
Okay.
And so in the last year, for example,
how many programs did you report bugs to?
Dude, very few.
Let me pull up the data right here.
I've got it.
All right.
So I'm looking here.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Probably barely more than ten.
Yeah.
Eleven is kind of where I'm at.
So very few programs.
And I think that's a function of me
focusing specifically on live hacking event targets
and also just not having a lot of time to hack this year
because of working on the rental property
and some other personal stuff that's come up.
You know, I've pretty much only been working hard
on the live hacking events
and then working on other programs on the side.
Yeah.
And one follow-up question to the thing about networking
and in the context of live hacking events.
So for people that don't know anybody,
they sort of probably follow your podcast.
They follow my media on Twitter,
but they don't know anybody personally.
How you think they can build those connections,
build those relationships?
Yeah.
I mean, the best way to build those relationships
is by interacting with people in meaningful ways
on Twitter and on Discord or X, excuse me.
You know, the security community,
particularly the bug bounty community,
is pretty active on X, on Twitter.
And so definitely be involved in that environment.
Discord as well.
I personally have a really hard time
keeping up with Discord.
Joel lives at Discord.
Joel is all over the place in Discord.
He's in every Discord server.
He's pretty actively responding to stuff
and I don't know how he does it.
But for me, it's Twitter.
And for example, let me give you someone
to look up to about this.
Rezo does a really good job of this, right?
He's constantly engaging in Discord.
He's constantly engaging on Twitter.
He's adding meaningful stuff to the conversation.
And yeah, I mean, everyone knows him.
Everyone takes notice of that.
And so it's definitely,
especially if your goal is to get to a live hacking event,
there is definitely some social aspect of it as well.
Okay.
And also in one of the,
I think two or three episodes ago,
you talked about the mentorship with two of your students.
What did you learn while teaching them?
What were the mistakes that they did
that you maybe didn't expect?
Yeah, well, you know,
one of the things that they talked about
in that podcast was this concept of Joshikihara,
which is a term that they coined in Japanese,
which essentially means like common sense harassment.
But essentially, there's a term for it already,
apparently called the curse of knowledge,
which we found out afterwards.
But essentially, once you've been in an environment
and you've had a set of knowledge for so long,
it's kind of hard for you to consider
what life is like without that knowledge
and that other people may not have that knowledge.
And so I definitely found
that I need to be a little bit more thorough
with my explanations,
especially since I've been doing this,
you know, since I was 12 or 13.
So most of my life, most of my cognizant life,
I've been doing this.
So it's a little bit hard for me
to put myself in their shoes.
I also learned the importance of the Socratic method,
which is essentially teaching via asking questions
and also just a variant on that,
which is teaching via, you know, teaching
and then having them teach it back to you.
That has a lot of value.
And if they can't teach it back to you correctly,
then they don't fully understand it.
And so that's definitely a high value principle as well.
And for the audience here
that don't have any mentor
and most of the audience don't have any mentor,
don't write a DM to Justin to mentor you
because he won't, that's one point.
And the second is,
you can also implement sort of learning
by asking questions
when you just publish stuff on your blog or on Twitter.
Simply you can write about anything that you learn,
some experience you've had,
some challenge you solved,
some anything that's sort of in your learning journey.
Because I know it from the beginning of the channel,
like the beginning of my channel was basically this,
was basically, oh, I think this report is cool
and I think I understand it.
But when I started to actually make a video about it,
I was a lot of the times realizing
I did not understand it at all.
It was only scratching the surface.
So it's a really, really good way to actually understand
because you're also prepared for other people
to sort of read it.
So you want to make sure
that you will not be wrong here in a stupid way.
So it's really, really good.
Yeah, I totally agree with that.
And just to echo,
even if you don't understand something fully
or if you can't fully exploit something
or you just find some weird quirk,
you can blog about that.
You can write about that.
You can tweet about that.
And people from the community
will sort of come along and be like,
oh, that's interesting
or nah, here's the solution for that.
That's easy, that sort of thing.
In either way, you learn.
So that's really cool.
And just going back to the mentorship note,
like you pointed out, Greg,
I would love to mentor all of you,
but I get way too many mentorship requests
and I can't even handle responding to my DMs,
let alone establishing a mentor relationship with people.
So I would definitely encourage people
to check out the pinned tweet that I've got
on how to essentially go from zero to 100K in Bug Bounty.
That kind of lays out a little bit of a flow on it.
And also, like you said, collaborate.
Put stuff out for the community.
You don't always need a mentor.
Sometimes you just need somebody to motivate you
to be your hacking partner.
If you look at Shubbs and Nafi,
the reason they both had a lot of success in the industry,
both of them would credit largely to the competition
between the two of them,
trying to outperform each other,
trying to figure out how did he do that,
you know, that sort of thing.
That sort of competition is really good for growth as well.
Yeah, and one other thing that you mentioned in that episode
was that, I think it was that episode,
that full-time Bug Bounty Hunter
should have a grind mentality.
Can you explain what did you mean?
It's a little bit tricky with that.
And I guess that's largely contextually dependent.
I'm not 100% sure that that's for everyone.
But at the end of the day,
this is not an easy job to do,
being a full-time Bug Bounty Hunter.
And there's going to be a lot of time
where you are frustrated with dupes,
or you're frustrated like I am right now,
or you're frustrated with, you know,
how much income you made,
or maybe this web application is just,
you know, beating you up
and you can't find any bones on it,
you know, and it just feels like
you're getting punched in the gut.
And so it's important to persevere through that
and realize that that's all part of the journey.
And as I'm saying this, I'm preaching to myself here
because, you know, it's hard to live that out.
And I struggle with that today and yesterday.
And oftentimes there's periods of relief from that
where I'm not really thinking about it.
But the times when it does happen,
it's very important to rely on your friends
for encouragement,
rely on your, you know, significant other,
rely on your religion,
for me, my relationship with Jesus,
to get that extra boost you need to kind of push through.
Yeah, and you also mentioned your wife, Mariah.
Yep, that's right.
You spell it a bit differently than we do.
We have the same name in foreign,
but we spell it differently.
That's why I sort of...
Yeah, yeah, it's M-A-R-I-A-H.
And, but almost everyone writes it Maria,
you know, without the H at the end.
So she responds to both.
Okay, but my question is,
how can a partner of a bug bounty hunter
support a bug bounty hunter?
And the intention of this question is
for bug bounty hunters out there
to show it to their partners.
Well, I should probably have Mariah over here
to talk about it.
And I think I will do a podcast episode with her sometimes
just kind of talk about this topic.
But I think Mariah is a very data-driven person
and a very practical person.
And so when she looks at the data and she says,
hey, Justin, you've been making more money
from bug bounty doing part-time
than you have been, you know, full-time bug bounty
or full-time job,
you should definitely go full-time bug bounty.
And that's just a very obvious choice for her.
And she's very confident in that decision.
And so that helps reassure me.
So her confidence in that sort of thing
and her confidence in the fact that
bug bounty is not a skill that you just lose,
which is somehow something that doesn't get into our heads
as hackers, you know?
I've been doing this five years.
And when I take a three-month break or whatever,
or two-month break or something like that,
and I come back, I feel rusty as heck.
And I'm like, man, that's it.
I don't got it anymore.
Like, you know, this is the end, you know?
And Mariah's like, you are so silly right now.
Like, just go hack stuff for a week.
You'll be fine.
And she's very encouraging in that regard.
And then also just practical stuff as well.
Like, you know, when I'm hacking,
she knows that I'm in the zone.
So I'm not as emotional when I respond,
or emotive in any way, you know?
Sometimes I talk like a robot,
and she understands that that's just because I'm in the zone.
And sometimes I forget to eat,
and she'll bring me, you know, healthy food.
And sometimes I forget to drink water,
and she'll bring me water.
And so, you know, those sort of things
really mean a lot to me.
They really show love very strongly.
And I don't know how I would do it without her.
So.
Yeah, so I'd really love to listen to an episode of her show.
It was a great idea.
And now let's go to the next part,
where let's talk about critical thinking.
And the first question is,
why to share your knowledge
when you could just keep it for yourself?
Yeah, that's a great question, man.
My dad asks me this every single time I see him,
because he's like,
don't give away the hacking secrets.
Like, this is your secret sauce.
Don't share it, you know?
And I understand what he's saying
from like the perspective of,
you know, trying to protect my income
and not sharing it with competitors
and stuff like that.
But at the end of the day,
the only reason I learned to hack as well as I have
is because people have shared stuff.
It would have been very hard for me to go from zero to,
this is, you know, now I understand how to hack things.
So one of it, a part of it is giving back to the community.
But another piece of it is just that
I want other people to succeed.
And it's one of my greatest joys in life
to see, you know, somebody who's learning bug bounty,
sort of grasp a topic and become very excited about it.
And I wish I could do that individually
with each and every person.
You know, like you said,
the people reaching out to me to get mentored.
I would love to mentor each and every one of you.
If I had the time, I would do it.
Because it brings me so much joy
to see ideas click and vulnerabilities found.
But I don't.
And so I figured I would do this more at scale via a podcast.
And yeah, I think there's also something
to just be said for having an audience.
That's very helpful for, I guess,
being respected in the industry.
And it's very helpful for
if I wanted to start any businesses in the future,
launching it from having an audience
is way better than launching it from not having an audience.
So, and then the final thing is,
I always wanted a bug bounty podcast
that brings sort of the conversation,
the awesome conversations and connections
you have with other hackers at the live hacking events
that brings that, you know, to our every single week.
And so that's kind of what we're shooting for
with the podcast is like,
let's talk about this stuff at a very high level,
at a level where, you know,
if you're not at that level,
then you have a good picture of what it looks like.
And if you are at that level,
then this is intellectually engaging for you.
And you can enjoy that from an intellectual perspective.
So that's kind of what we're shooting for.
Yeah, that's great.
Where does the name come from?
The Critical Thinking Bug Bounty Podcast?
Yeah, it's a little bit,
the name is a little bit weird, man,
because like, from an SEO perspective,
like very hard to rank for critical thinking, right?
But the name was actually generated
by the early versions of ChatGPT.
And essentially what I said was like,
hey, we're gonna do a bug bounty podcast.
We'd like, you know, some cool,
engaging sort of punny name maybe.
And we gave it a bunch of terms
that are related to the industry.
And it came up with critical thinking.
And I was like,
the other one that was kind of in our,
there was an option was like,
I think it was like bounty bites or something like that.
Or maybe it's like, yeah, I believe that was it.
But that sounded too short.
You know, we were gonna do an hour,
hour and a half long podcast.
So that wasn't really long enough.
And so we landed on critical thinking as a pun
for thinking about critical vulnerabilities.
And actually we are starting to rank for it.
So I'm excited about that.
Does the podcast make any money
or do you sort of lose money on it?
No, I lose money on it every single month.
Yeah, we're in the stages of monetizing it now.
We have some really exciting ideas,
both for the community and for our wallets,
you know, regarding the podcast.
So you can definitely expect in the future
a critical thinking discord to open up
with under Joel's diligent, you know, discord skills
that will have some discord subscriptions.
We'll have, we're working to develop
some really awesome swag.
We're not gonna do any mid swag.
Like this is gonna be awesome swag.
We're working on that.
And then we're also working with various companies
to sponsor the podcast and try to get
that going on a regular basis.
Yeah, that's great.
Because you really do a good job.
And I think it was definitely a missing piece
in the industry.
So you definitely deserve to at least
not lose on it every month.
Yeah, you know, and I also, I wanna get it to a point
where I can just focus on the content.
Because right now I'm doing like a bunch
of social media stuff.
And I'm doing a bunch of administrative stuff
and that sort of thing.
And I'm paying money for it to be edited every month.
And it's definitely worth it.
But at some point, I would like to have the podcast income
covering all of that.
And, you know, allow me to hire someone
to do social media and just focus on
me developing the content.
And I think that's when critical thinking
is really gonna start.
The quality of the episodes will go up a lot
because I'll have more time to devote
to actually crafting the content.
Yeah, yeah.
That's gonna be great.
And when you create the private Discord,
I will be the first customer.
Ah, thanks, man.
I appreciate that.
Yeah, every single time you mention BBR Premium
on Twitter, I just get instantly,
instantly subscriptions coming in.
So thank you.
Thank you for this.
I'm glad.
I'll have to do that on a regular basis then.
Okay, Justin.
Thank you so much for joining me today.
I think we covered a broad range of topics.
And I think there are a lot of things for viewers
that they can sort of save in their heads,
probably maybe in their notes
for the more note-taking type viewers.
So thank you for this very interesting conversation.
Of course, man.
Thanks for having me on.
Justin gave me and you loads of useful Bug Bounty tips.
But if you are still hungry for more,
subscribe to the Critical Thinking Bug Bounty podcast
and check out, for example,
this episode with Alex Chapman.
Also, Black Friday is coming and don't miss it
because it's the only BBR Premium promotion
for the whole year.